©
© P @ rM ! NdeR
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ ™
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ ™ Mobile - + 919815899536
MRS. FISHER : My babies !
Arthur ?
JOSEPH : Daddy ?
Coming .
Do you like it , Daddy ?
Very much .
You didn 't look at it properly .
Of course I did .
That 's me , that 's Nanny ,
that 's Mummy , and that 's you .
Why do I look so sad ?
That 's what your face looks like .
ARTHUR : Oh , it is , is it ?
I wish you didn 't have to go away from me .
Me , too .
But we 'll have the whole weekend
in the countryside , won 't we ?
See , tomorrow ,
then Thursday ,
and then we 're back together .
Not long at all .
You look just like your mother .
Have you got the train tickets ?
Yes , we 've got the train tickets .
And you know all the times ?
Yes , we know the times .
Okay , I 've got to go .
Don 't want to be late .
Go , we 'll be fine .
We 'll see you Friday .
See you . Wave bye-bye .
I know you 've had it rough , Kipps ,
and I 'm sympathetic to your situation .
But we can 't carry passengers .
We 're a law firm , not a charity .
Good .
I take it Tomes has briefed you
on Mrs. Alice Drablow of Eel Marsh House .
Died . Last month .
Years since I went there , of course .
The old widow didn 't greatly care for visitors .
No children ?
A boy . Died young .
Many years ago .
I 'll let you have the details
to read on your journey .
But , principally , you 're going to go through
Mrs. Drablow 's documents .
Make sure we 've got her final will .
There 's a mountain of paperwork at the house .
It all needs to be gone through . Every page .
Very good .
We 've been dealing with a local man , Jerome .
But he 's not really been cooperating .
What I 'm hoping , Kipps ,
is that you 'll seize this chance
to prove your dedication
to pursuing a future with this firm .
This is your final warning .
GIRL : Mummy ?
Mummy . My darling .
DOCTOR : Mr. Kipps .
It 's a boy .
I 'm very sorry , Mr. Kipps .
Have we passed Crythin Gifford yet ?
Next stop .
So , you 're up from London ?
I am .
Trying to sell Eel Marsh House ?
You won 't find a local buyer .
Are you staying at The Gifford Arms ?
Yes .
It 's a bit of a walk from the station .
I can give you a lift .
It 's on my way home .
Thank you .
Samuel Daily .
Arthur Kipps .
ARTHUR : It 's a beautiful car , Mr. Daily .
DAILY : First one in the county .
Still scares the locals .
Here we are .
Well , thank you .
Very good to talk to you , Mr. Daily .
Mr. Kipps ?
Would you like to have supper
with my wife and me tomorrow evening ?
You know , we don 't get to see many new faces here .
Besides , the food in there ,
reckon even a dog wouldn 't eat it .
That 'd be lovely . Thank you .
Night .
ARTHUR : Good evening .
I 've a room booked until Sunday . Mr. Kipps .
No , I 'm not finding any booking .
My office had telegraphed ahead .
Well , we 're packed to the rafters . So ...
Evening . Good evening .
I was just telling Mr. Kipps that we don 't have any room .
Well , we can 't have him out in this weather , can we ?
Not in the rain .
We must have something , just for tonight .
We don 't .
Unless you want to put him in the attic ?
Fine .
It 's this way .
Actually , I was hoping to stay till the weekend .
My son and his nanny are traveling up to join me .
Oh , I see .
If a holiday is what you 're after , sir ,
you 'd honestly be better off further inland .
It gets awfully cold here , what with the sea mists .
BIRD : Sea mist . Sea mist .
It 's this way .
How old is your son ?
He 's four .
Lovely age .
Thank you .
Goodnight .
In .
Hello ?
Mrs. Jerome ?
Mr. Kipps ? Yes .
My husband went to meet you at The Gifford Arms .
This is Mr. Kipps .
I made it clear to your firm
that there was no need for you to make the journey .
We could have sent all the relevant documents
to London .
In any event ,
you 'll find all the legal papers in here .
Mr. Fisher tells me you 're leaving today .
Not until I 've taken care of all Mrs. Drablow 's paperwork .
All in there , as I said .
No , at the house .
I 'm told there 's quite a substantial amount .
I don 't expect to be finished until Friday , at least .
It 's not possible .
The Gifford Arms is fully booked for the week .
I shall have to contact my office .
Do you have a telephone ?
Not even Mr. Daily has a telephone , sir .
You 'll not find one in Crythin Gifford .
Fine . I 'll send a telegram .
The Post Office is closed on Wednesday morning .
The London train leaves in half an hour .
My colleague , Keckwick , is waiting outside
with your luggage .
It 's a pleasure to meet you , Mr. Kipps .
Mr. Keckwick , a change of plans .
I 'm not catching the train .
You 'll take me to Eel Marsh House .
Jerome paid me to take you to the station .
Make it six and I 'll think about it .
Six shillings ?
You 'll not find anyone else willing to take you there .
There you are .
Can you pick me up at 3 : 00 ? I can 't .
I need to get back to the mainland
before the tide comes in ,
else I 'll be stuck here for the day .
It will be out again by 5 : 00 .
I 'll come back for you then .
5 : 00 then .
Come on , then .
Hello ?
Who 's there ?
MAN : Get the boy !
Keckwick !
Mummy !
MAN : Get the boy !
ARTHUR : Constable , I 'm telling you , I heard an accident .
No one has used Nine Lives Causeway for years , sir .
Not since the little Drablow boy
was drowned in the marshes .
Eel Marsh House , it 's empty .
It 's not , though .
I saw a woman there .
Excuse me one moment , sir .
Sir , my sister needs help .
What 's the matter ?
What 's your name , darling ?
Her name is Victoria Hardy .
What happened , Victoria ?
Did something bad happen ?
She drank some lye .
Our mum was out .
Lye . Oh , God . Constable !
Is she going to die ? Constable !
It 's going to be all right .
Darling , just let me look at you ...
Constable !
MRS. HARDY : No !
No , my baby !
Hello ?
Mrs. Fisher ?
It 's getting late .
You 'll miss your London train .
I can 't leave yet .
Please don 't go back to Eel Marsh House .
Why ?
Mr. Kipps , you said you have a son ?
Yes .
Go home to him .
Cherish him . Love him .
I wouldn 't be here if I didn 't .
©
© P @ rM ! NdeR
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ
Mr. Kipps . Mr. Daily .
Glad you could make it . My pleasure .
I 'm just bidding my son , Nicholas , goodnight .
My condolences , Mr. Daily .
It was a long while ago .
There 's a place ready in there for my wife and me ,
so we can all be together again one day . Come .
I heard about the girl in the village .
Terrible . Are you all right ?
Yes .
My wife doesn 't know
and I 'd be grateful if you could avoid the subject .
Indeed , the subject of children altogether ,
if at all possible .
He would have been about your age now .
MRS. DAILY : Thank you , Archer .
There you are , dear .
Mr. Kipps , I 've been so looking forward
to meeting you .
I 'm sorry , I must look a bit of a mess .
I found myself without a room .
Oh ! Well , then he must stay with us , mustn 't he , Samuel ?
Indeed he must , my dear .
Arthur . Thank you .
The twins won 't be dining with us tonight , Archer .
Samuel , I 'm sure Mr. Kipps won 't mind .
Not at all .
Emily !
Thank you .
There .
Now , say hello to Mr. Kipps .
Hello .
Thank you , Archer .
There .
You 're married , Mr. Kipps ?
No , don 't gobble .
That 's rude .
Any children ? A son .
Oh , that 's lovely .
You don 't want to end up like us .
Wealthiest folk in the county and no one to leave it to .
Did he tell you about Nicholas ? Elizabeth .
That 's him .
I painted that myself .
I love to paint and sketch .
It 's lovely .
Nicholas loved to sketch , too .
He still does .
Elizabeth , please .
He wants to draw you a picture .
DAILY : Elizabeth .
Elizabeth , no !
Elizabeth !
Archer , the medication !
No . Medication !
No , no .
I thought some company would do her good .
Please , think nothing of it .
She 's convinced it 's our son speaking through her .
You don 't believe in this spiritualism stuff , do you ?
I didn 't .
But since my wife passed away , I don 't know .
Ah . Forgive me . I didn 't ...
Sometimes I feel she 's still with me .
Sometimes I just
feel she 's there . In the room .
Trying to reach me .
Well , you must be careful , Arthur .
These charlatans with all their talk about séances
and contacting the dead .
They prey on those most in need .
They do more harm than good .
I think the worst they do is disappoint .
I have to keep looking .
It 's not natural to lose someone so young .
But if we open the door to superstition ,
where does that lead ?
It 's just chasing shadows , Arthur .
When we die , we go up there .
We don 't stay down here .
MRS. DAILY : Come on .
Come on . Lie down .
ARTHUR : I 'll lose my job
if I don 't get this paperwork done .
If Jerome gives me some help , I can go and meet my boy .
I doubt if Jerome will be much help to you .
Stay , Spider .
Mr. Jerome ?
GIRL : Go away !
I 'm not going to hurt you .
You killed Victoria Hardy .
Get away from me !
Go !
Go ! Go !
What the hell is going on ?
Complete nonsense .
Let 's get you to the house .
You should have left .
You should have gone when we told you to .
John .
His little girl is dead .
You saw her .
You saw that woman at the house .
Oh , for God 's sake , take him home .
This isn 't helping him .
All your superstitious rubbish .
You think this is superstitious rubbish
that took your boy ?
All right .
I 'll take him to the station .
DAILY : Pay no attention to them .
They 're still living in the Dark Ages .
ARTHUR : But I did see someone at the house .
Trust me , Arthur .
It 's just an old place cut off from the world .
The sooner the house is sorted out and sold ,
the sooner people can move on . Here .
This 'll keep you going .
The late tide is due at 11 : 00 .
I 'll come back for you then .
It 's fine .
I 'd rather just work through the night .
Well , take the dog .
Come on , girl .
Just for company .
Don 't go chasing shadows , Arthur .
JENNET : Dear Alice ,
you leave me no option but to give up my son .
If you have your doctors
deem me mentally unfit to raise my child ,
what can I do ?
You and Charles can take him from me ,
but he is mine ,
mine , he can never be yours .
Jennet .
Dear Alice ,
I find it hard to express the depth of betrayal
from you , my own sister ,
at your refusal to let me visit my son
or even give him my birthday cards .
I begin to believe
you 're not doing this for the good of the boy ,
but to cause me pain .
He is mine .
If you won 't let me see him , I will find a way .
You didn 't try to save him .
You just saved yourself .
You didn 't even give him a proper burial .
You just left him there in the mud .
His blood is on your hands .
I will never forgive you .
Rot in hell .
He will never be yours .
Who 's there ?
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ ™
©
© P @ rM ! NdeR
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ
You don 't believe me , do you ?
I believe even the most rational mind
can play tricks in the dark .
I saw them , Sam .
I saw her and her boy .
No . The boy was lost to the marsh .
His body was never recovered .
I saw them .
Oh , my God !
No , don 't ...
Lucy !
Arthur !
No ! No ! Arthur !
Stay there .
I 'm going to come and get you .
No !
Arthur ?
Here .
I remember
when the Jeromes lost their first child .
They decided to have another . Lucy .
They locked her up to protect her .
Not that you can ever replace ...
She was there , Sam .
You 're tired .
Get some rest .
What happened to him , Mrs. Daily ?
He was playing at the beach with his friends
and they said the tide must have caught them off guard .
You 've seen her , haven 't you ?
She was there this morning in the fire .
She 's always there .
You mustn 't blame yourself .
Blame myself for what ?
For not listening to the others .
For not staying away from the house .
What ? I don 't understand .
Whenever she 's been seen ,
on the causeway , on the marsh , in the grounds of the house ,
however briefly and whoever by ,
there has always been one sure and certain result .
Yes ?
In some violent or dreadful circumstance ,
a child has died .
So many ... So many children .
So many children .
The Fishers ' daughters and Jeromes ' eldest .
Keckwick 's son , my Nicholas .
How ?
Oh ... Mrs. Daily ?
Mrs. Daily ?
She makes us ...
She makes us do it .
She makes us .
They took her boy away .
So now she takes us .
She saw you .
She 's coming .
Elizabeth ! Sam !
Sam ! Elizabeth !
No , Elizabeth . No ! No !
Elizabeth .
ARTHUR : Joseph .
If we can get the telegram off now ,
we can catch them before they get on the train .
How could you take me to Eel Marsh ?
If even a small part of you feared the stories were true ?
But I never believed them .
No , you didn 't want to .
There 's a difference .
I had no choice , Arthur .
Either Nicholas is in a better place
waiting for us to be reunited one day ,
or he 's lost .
Now which would you have chosen to believe ?
Forgive me , Sam , but my son is alive .
He 's on his way here .
DAILY : Oh , no .
The next village is over an hour away .
They 'll have left by then .
What time is the tide back out ?
5 : 00 . Why ?
If we can reunite Jennet Humfrye with her son ,
perhaps she 'll finally be at peace .
They never recovered the child 's body , Arthur .
But you have something they never had .
Arthur ?
Sam , I feel it .
It 's just beneath my feet .
Just give me a moment while I tie it .
Be careful .
Arthur ?
Oh , my God .
Keep driving .
Don 't stop !
The pedal 's on the floor .
I 've found the boy .
Can you go any farther ?
The engine 's overheating !
Come on .
Sam , please , it 's sinking .
Hurry !
Here , here .
Let 's just put him in the ground , Arthur .
Let 's get it over with .
Sam ,
there 's something I need to do first .
They 're lost .
They need to find each other .
Nearly time now .
Come on .
Nicholas ?
NICHOLAS : Daddy ?
Arthur !
Arthur .
I think she 's gone .
Thank you .
JENNET : I will never forgive you for letting my boy die .
I will never forgive .
Never forgive .
Never forgive . Never forgive .
One step , two step . Good boy .
Joseph ! Daddy !
Joseph , this is my friend , Sam .
Hello , Sam . Hello , Joseph .
It 's very nice to meet you .
Change of plans .
We 're not staying here tonight .
We 're going straight back to London .
Can you fetch us some tickets ?
I 'll explain on the way .
You 're sure you don 't want to rest up before you go ?
Yes , I just want to get him home .
I understand .
Three tickets back to London , please .
Will you and Elizabeth be all right ?
We will .
Then you must come down to London and visit us .
Elizabeth would love that .
ARTHUR : Sam ?
Daddy ?
Who 's that lady ?
That 's your Mummy .
©
© P @ rM ! NdeR
© P @ rM ! NdeR M @ nkÖÖ